pinpointe.com 2018-12-26

# Pinpointe's Email Marketing Privacy Policy. We Respect Your Privacy

We respect and are committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy lets you know how your personal information is collected and used, both by Pinpointe and our clients who use our hosted application. We have created this privacy policy so that you can understand the care with which we intend to treat your personal information. If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please contact us.

### Our Commitment to You

Your personal information such as contact name and email address will be kept confidential. It is never sold, given away, and will only be shared with another entity if we are required by law or in the very limited and controlled circumstances described under the section **Personally Identifiable Information and Our Use of Cookies**.

Your customers’ contact information is strictly confidential and will never be shared with any third party unless required by law.

We may send you automated emails asking you if you’d like to activate, or de-activate your free trial (if you don’t use it after a reasonable time period). We like to remove dormant accounts from our system, and to save you the monthly billing for an unused account.

In order to use Pinpointe, you must first fill in the registration form and create a user name and password. During registration you are required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use this information to send you a confirmation link, which is used to activate your account.

### Your Customer Lists

Your lists are stored on our secure Pinpointe servers. We do not, under any circumstances, contact your lists, market to your lists, sell your lists, or share your lists with any other party, unless required to by law. Your lists are kept strictly confidential.

Only carefully selected, authorized personnel have access (for customer service and abuse-monitoring purposes) to view system accounts and campaigns.

We do not hold your lists hostage. You may export (download) your lists from Pinpointe at any time. They are your property.

### Transactional and Mandatory Emails That We’ll Be Sending You

These are the types of emails you can expect to receive from Pinpointe if you sign up for our email marketing services.

Email Receipts – When you use your credit card to place an order with Pinpointe, you will naturally be receiving an email receipt for your purchase.

Terminating your account – If you have not logged into Pinpointe’s system for 6 months, your account is considered “dormant.” To keep our system clean, we periodically send follow-up emails to dormant accounts with a link allowing them to permanently shut down their accounts.

System Alerts – All registered, active (non-dormant), Pinpointe user accounts may receive mandatory “System Alert” messages which usually consist of: planned outages, system improvements (that may directly affect your account), version updates, point releases, abuse warnings, and important customer service information. Our “System Alert” messages are brief and non-promotional in nature. We promise to keep them as boring as possible.

Automated responses – If you submit a help ticket to Pinpointe, our system may send an automatic survey email requesting your feedback on how your issue was resolved. We use this information to improve our customer support. In addition, based on your usage patterns and activity within your Pinpointe customer account, you may receive automatic emails informing you of various product features, methods to improve your user experience or occasional surveys asking for your feedback as a valued Pinpointe customer. We use these communications to constantly improve our customer service and to provide you the best possible product. All automated responses are non-promotional in nature. Submitting a help ticket, answering a survey or replying to an automatic email to request additional information from us will never add you to any mailing list.

### Promotional Emails That We Send

We do not send promotional emails unless you have requested them.

From time to time, we send a “Pinpointe Tips ‘N Tricks Newsletter” email newsletter. Pinpointe email marketing services include a subscription to Pinpointe’s bi-monthly Customer Tips ‘n Tricks newsletter for B2B marketers. You may of course opt-out at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe link” that we include in every newsletter.

### Personally Identifiable Information and Our Use of Cookies

Pinpointe uses certain third party-developed applications to enhance our ability to monitor, aggregate and store our customers’ usage patterns within their respective Pinpointe account. This information is used by Pinpointe to send various forms of communication such as emails and in-app messages to our customers in an effort to provide additional information and suggestions regarding our product’s features and capabilities, or to request customer feedback. These third parties never share your personally identifiable information with any outside entity, nor does Pinpointe ever share any customer financial or billing information beyond those situations disclosed elsewhere in this section or under the section, **Safeguarding Your Information**.

For more information on how Pinpointe endeavors to protect the personal information (“Personal Information”) of our customers’ end user contacts (“Recipients”), please read our revised Terms of Service and our Data Processing Addendum (“DPA”). In addition, for a more general description of what the new European Economic Area (“EEA”) General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) rules mean to individuals, their rights in controlling how their Personal Information is used and stored, how this affects those entities that utilize this information, and how Pinpointe has modified its own processes in response to these new regulations, please refer to our articles entitled, [**GDPR & Email Marketing | How Will Europe’s New Privacy Laws Affect Your Email Marketing**](https://www.pinpointe.com/blog/how-gdpr-affects-email-marketing), and **[How Pinpointe Is Preparing For GDPR](https://www.pinpointe.com/blog/pinpointe-preparing-gdpr)**.

We may store session information, so that registered users do not have to login every time they visit the site.

We do not partner with or have special relationships with any ad server companies.

When we send emails to our own registered Pinpointe customers, we track who opened and who clicked. We do this to measure the performance of our email campaigns, and to improve our offerings to specific customer segments.

Some of our Web pages utilize “cookies” and other tracking technologies. Collected information may at times be tied to the users’ personally identifiable information, so that we can provide appropriate offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is also used to tailor a user’s visit to our Website and to direct pertinent marketing information to them.

Pinpointe customers: if your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update your account or deactivate it in the “Account Settings” area in Pinpointe, or by contacting us by telephone, or by sending an email to accounts@pinpointe.com.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.

We use other third parties to handle secure credit card transaction processing from our site. When you make purchases on Pinpointe, we send your billing information as necessary for the third party to process your order. Pinpointe does not store or retain your personal credit card information unless you request that we do in order to process your order(s).

### Safeguarding Your Information

To protect your information, we use a credit processing vendor – we do not retain your credit card information. Our vendor uses the latest 128-bit Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology for secure transactions. In addition, our vendor is certified as compliant with card association security initiatives, such as the Visa Cardholder Information Security Program (CISP), MasterCard® (SDP), and Discover Information Security and Compliance (DISC).

Pinpointe accounts require a username (in the form of an email address, such as “user@company.com”) and password to log in. When you’re finished using Pinpointe, please click the “log out” link in the top right corner of your screen, to prevent someone from using your computer to access your account.

### Breach of Security Policy

Pinpointe will notify you if a breach in security results in an unauthorized intrusion into our system which directly or materially affects you or your subscribers, and will subsequently report the corrective action taken in response to the intrusion.

It should be noted however, that when you send an email marketing campaign, it bounces around the Internet from server to server, and can theoretically be read by prying eyes and nosy techies and government officials. We have no control over the security and privacy of your emails and subscribers after you hit the “Send” button from Pinpointe. So if you’re sending extremely private information to your recipients, and require absolute secrecy, email is not the way to go.

### Children under 13

We do not knowingly provide accounts, or market to, or solicit information from, children under the age of 13. Our terms stipulate you must be 18 years or older to use the Pinpointe system.

_The above information is true and accurate as of  July 31, 2017._
